我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
but, in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats,
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
and I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我叫闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
-他可是你哥哥  西斯科  -没得选啊
- He's your brother, Cisco. - Not by choice.
妈妈告诉我你还在尖端科研实验室工作呢
So Mom tells me you're still working at S.T.A.R. Labs.
我们没有西斯科可不行
We couldn't do what we do without Cisco.
他很忠诚  就像条狗
Oh, he's loyal. Just like a dog.
我们谈好条件了
We had a deal.
用你的速度交换沃利
用我的速度换沃利的命
My speed for Wally's life.
交出他来  速度给你
Hand him over, and it's yours.
神速力在脱离他的身体
The Speed Force is leaving his body.
他要变回普通人了
He's becoming human again.
我知道你心里是在乎过我的
I know some piece of you did care for me.
求求你  放了他
Please, let him go.
凯特琳
Caitlin!
你会重新获得速度的  艾伦
You are gonna get your speed back, Allen,
而我会帮你实现
and I'm gonna help you do that.
-如何实现  -再制造一次粒子加速器爆炸
- How? - By creating another particle accelerator explosion.
巴里  有一起高速追捕
Barry, there's a high-speed chase
向米尔顿大街以南移动
heading south on Milton Ave.
我们甩掉他们了
We lost 'em.
不过可甩不掉他
Not gonna lose him, though.
你想打赌吗
You wanna bet?
你想玩吗
Oh! Oh! You wanna play?
好吧  好的
Okay! All right.
准备好出招吧
Get ready to bring it!
-他们速度没有慢下来  -那肯定啊
- They're not slowing down. - Of course not!
那就是出路  隧道  走隧道
There's our out--the tunnel! Take the tunnel!
他们进了第五大街的隧道
They're headed for the Fifth Street tunnel.
卫星投射不到那里
Satellite can't project in there.
什么  你现在才想起这事吗
What? You just thought of this now?
我没想到他们会试图和闪电侠竞速
I didn't think he'd actually try to outrun The Flash!
闪电  抛掷闪电
Lightning. Lightning toss!
他想要抛掷闪电
He wants to do the lightning toss.
不行  没有闪电  那是全息投影  记得吗
Nope. No lightning. It's a hologram. Remember?
只要...
Just...
不不不  用绕圈
No. No, no. The wind-up!
这样就可以挡住他们的视野了
So we can block their field of vision.
是的  没错
Yes! Of course.
好了  西斯科
All right, Cisco.
你在地下室花费的无数游戏时间
This is where all those countless hours gaming in your basement
就要派上用场了
are about to pay off.
手指  别让我失望
Fingers, don't fail me now.
勒罗伊...
Leerooooy...!
我的眼睛  这是什么
Ah, my eyes! What is this?
举起手来
Hands in the air!
我得缓一缓
I need a breather.
我还以为这全息投影不会起作用
I didn't think this hologram thing was gonna work,
但目前为止还不错
but so far, so good.
我是想  如果他们能够让图派克
I mean, I figured if they could get 2Pac
再一次在演唱会上说唱
rapping again at a concert,
我们肯定也能
we could definitely
再让闪电侠在中城飞奔
get The Flash running around Central City.
-这不是长久之计  -又来了
- It's not gonna last. - There it is.
过不了多久就会有人发现
It's not gonna be long before someone figures out,
"等等  你什么都没说"
"Oh, wait. You never say anything.
"你什么都不碰  等等  你还从来不进屋"
You never touch anything. Oh, wait. You never go indoors"
好吧  巴里没有了神速
Okay, well, without Barry's speed,
也就只能这样将就了
this is as good an idea as any.
事实上  我不能赞同
Actually, I beg to differ.
我想更好的解决办法
I think a better idea,
不是玩什么"暴徒与全息投影"
instead of playing "Hoodlums and Holograms"
而是应该重建粒子加速器
would be to rebuild the particle accelerator
恢复巴里的速度
to get Barry's speed back.
-威尔斯  这你说了很多次了  -没错
- Yeah, Wells, that's what you keep saying. - That's right.
看看那爆炸将这城市变成了什么样
Look at what that explosion did to this city.
更不要说  上一次我们试图做类似的事时
Not to mention, last time we tried something like that,
我们把宇宙炸了一个洞  还搞出了
we blew a hole in the universe and created, like,
五十个通向你们地球的传送门
50 portals to your Earth.
这也是极速和他的手下
Which is exactly how Zoom and his henchmen
-来到这里的原因  -我跟你说过了
- got here in the first place. - I told you.
我知道怎么控制那爆炸
I know how to contain the explosion.
-真的吗  - 是的
- Really? - Yes.
你知道怎么抑制暗物质爆炸吗
You know how to contain a dark matter explosion
那爆炸上一次辐射到了整个中城
that, last time, just radiated all of Central City?
你在你的地球上试过了  记得吗
You tried this on your Earth, remember?
结果可不怎么好
Didn't go so well.
而且  即便你能控制它
And, even if you could contain it,
我记得你说过巴里不能再
I thought you said that Barry couldn't
接入神速力了
tap into the Speed Force anymore.
他第一次获得超能力时也没有连接上
It wasn't connected the first time he got his powers.
我有你们那个威尔斯的数据
Look, I have your Wells's data.
这个地球的哈里森·威尔斯  我有他的技术
The Harrison Wells from this Earth, I have his science.
我知道你身体里需要什么化学物质
I know what chemicals need to be in your body.
我知道闪电和粒子加速器爆炸释放的暗物质
I know how the lightning needs to bond with the dark matter
应该如何结合在一起
from the particle accelerator explosion.
我可以创造相同的条件恢复你的速度
I can recreate the circumstances to get you your speed back.
会成功的
This will work.
你们那伎俩  是用不久的
Your subterfuge... is not gonna last.
而更重要的是  它救不了斯诺
But more importantly... it's not gonna save Snow.
它无法带回你们的凯特琳
It's not gonna bring your Caitlin back.
你应该准备好面对极速归来
You wanna be ready should Zoom return--
如果极速归来  或是当极速归来时
if Zoom returns-when Zoom returns--
只有一个办法可以面对他
there is only one way to do it,
那就是恢复你的速度
and that's by getting your speed back.
你怎么样
How are you?
-你来了  -是啊
- You made it. - Yeah.
看看你  进来吧  暖和点
Look at this. Come inside. Get warm.
好
Yeah. Wow.
-来这里真是好一段车程  -没错
- Sure is a pretty drive up here. - It is that.
我不禁好奇  极速者怎么还需要开车
I can't help but wonder why a speedster needs a car.
因为我不再是极速者了
Because I am no longer a speedster.
你失去超能力了吗
You've lost your powers?
我为了救乔的儿子沃利放弃了超能力
I gave them up to save Wally, Joe's son.
极速抓了他  不把速度给他  他就...
Zoom had him, so it was either give him my speed, or...
我不能让沃利死掉
I couldn't let Wally die.
对  你不能
No. You couldn't.
现在杰伊抓走了凯特琳
Now Jay has taken Caitlin,
我们不知道怎么救她
and we have no idea how to save her.
杰伊抓了凯特琳
Jay took Caitlin?
杰伊  对
Jay. It's--yeah.
原来杰伊·加里克不是地球二的闪电侠
Turns out Jay Garrick is not the Flash from Earth-2.
他是极速
He's Zoom.
加里克
Garrick?
加里克  对  怎么了
Garrick, yeah. Why?
是我母亲的娘家姓
My mom's maiden name.
或许...或许威尔斯是对的
Maybe... maybe Wells is right.
或许我应该找回超能力
Maybe I should try to get my powers back.
那你要怎么做
How would you do that?
再制造一次粒子加速器爆炸
By recreating the particle accelerator explosion.
再被闪电击中一次吗
And getting struck by lightning again?
这好像不是万全之策  对吗
That doesn't seem like the safest option, does it?
对
No.
我看到你成为闪电侠后成长了很多
I've watched you grow ever since you became The Flash,
我也为你的成长感到骄傲
and I am so proud of that man.
可你问问自己
But ask yourself,
你真的需要超能力
do you really need powers
才能成为那个人吗
in order to be that person?
只是好像我生命中每次发生什么好事
It just feels like every time something good happens in my life,
都会被夺走
it's taken away.
或许我们该对此做些什么了
Well, maybe it's time we did something about that.
看着像真空
It looks like the Vacuum.
真空是什么
Uh, what's the Vacuum?
看来地球二上没有《迷离档案》
No "Fringe" on Earth-2. Noted.
那是什么
What is that thing?
巴里得通过这个找回速度
That is how Barry's gonna get his speed back.
你在工作室就一直在忙这个
This is what you've been working on in the workshop?
总得有人担心极速的事
Someone has to worry about Zoom.
好了  巴里不能这么做
Okay. Barry cannot do this.
他必须这么做  拉蒙
He has to, Ramon.
你一直这么叫我  可那...
You keep calling me that, but that's--
丹堤
Dante?
你看到了什么  极速  看到极速了吗
What did you see? Zoom? Did you see Zoom?
没有
No.
我看见我哥哥了
I saw my brother.
我得走了
I got to go.
去看看大家在哪
See where everybody is.
亨利
Henry?
爱瑞丝  你好
Iris. Hi.
很高兴见到你
It's so good to see you.
我也是
Aw, you too.
我猜巴里要你回来待一段时间  对吧
I guess Barry dragged you back for a bit, huh?
可能就不走了
Looks like maybe for good.
等等  真的吗
Wait, what? Seriously?
对  我感觉和我儿子分开得够久了
Yeah, yeah, I figured I spent enough time away from my son.
你和爸爸说了吗
Have you told Dad?
没  我想亲自告诉他
No, I wanted to tell him in person.
好  他应该和沃利在中城警局
Yeah. I think he's with Wally at CCPD.
我给他打电话
I'll give him a call.
-见到你真好  -好  我们去收拾一下
- Good to see you. - Yeah. Let's get settled.
你姐姐打电话问我们什么时候到家
Your sister called, checking in when we'd be home.
-所以我们要走了吗  -谢谢
- As in, we need to get going? - Thanks.
你了解你姐姐
You know your sister.
好  走  快走
Okay, move it. Let's go.
你对这工作感到厌烦过吗
Do you ever get sick of this job?
当警察
Being a cop?
看来某人继承了韦斯特家
Oh, looks like someone inherited the West
"助人为乐"的基因
I-need-to-help-people gene.
闪电侠救了我之后  我就...
Ever since The Flash saved me, I just...
我不知道我这辈子是不是
I don't know if designing cars
就注定要做个汽车设计师
is what I'm meant to do with my life.
我相信一定有一件事
Well, I'm sure there's something out there
能满足你对速度的渴望
that'll satisfy your need for speed
实现你帮助他人的心愿  可在那之前
and helping people, but, until then,
你应该专注车辆设计
you should stick with engineering.
这更安全
It's much safer.
咱们得走了  不然辛格又要
We should get going before Singh comes up
给我安排任务了
with something for me to do.
极速
Zoom!
你好  老朋友
Hello, old friend.
离他远点
Stay away from him.
不准动
Do not move.
不然呢
Or what?
你们之前也开枪打过我
You've tried your guns on me once before.
不  别伤害他们
No! Don't hurt them.
放过他们  求你了
Let them go, please.
告诉所有人  我是这城市的主人
Tell everyone that this city is mine.
如果有人敢违背我
Anyone who disobeys me
就只有死路一条
will meet their end.
好  撤退
All right. Clear out!
凯特琳和极速在一起
Caitlin's with Zoom.
他为何要把她带到这里
Why would he bring her here?
为显示他的强大
To show power.
他在我的地球上就是这么干的
That's exactly what he did on my Earth.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
他做的第一件事就是杀人
The first thing he did was murder people.
屠杀了一群警察
Slaughtered a bunch of policemen.
然后招募他能找到的所有超能力者
Then recruited every meta-human he could find.
但凡反抗他的  也都被他干掉了
And those that disobeyed, he killed too.
-警察现在在哪里  -在警区外面
- Where are the police now? - Outside the precinct.
他会杀了他们的  乔  一个不剩
He'll kill them, Joe. He'll kill them all.
有凯特琳在就不会
Not with Caitlin with him.
他占领中城警局时  她就说服他别杀人
She talked him out of killing everyone when he took over CCPD.
所以我们就指望这个吗
That's what we're gonna rely on?
指望斯诺说服他吗
Snow talking him out of it?
乔  你要把他们全都带出去
Joe, you need to get those guys out of there.
把他们安排在吉特斯如何
What if they set up at Jitters?
好主意  那儿离警区只有一个街区
That's a good idea-- it's just a block away from the precinct.
然后呢  接下来呢
And then what? What happens next?
你见过极速在我的地球上做了什么
You saw what Zoom did on my Earth.
他在这里也会做同样的事
He will do the exact same thing here.
巴里  我们要恢复你的超能力
Barry, we need to get you your powers back.
-肯定有别的办法  -没有
- There must be another way. - There's not.
真的没有
There's not.
我去转告辛格
I'm gonna get word to Singh.
让他在吉特斯集结一个特别小组
Get him to set up a task force at Jitters.
-然后呢  -还不知道
- And then what? - I don't know yet,
但是我会保证沃利和杰西的安全
but I'm gonna make sure Wally and Jesse are safe.
你知道他们会找到办法阻止你吧
You know they're gonna figure out a way to stop you, right?
谁  巴里  威尔斯  警察吗
Who? Barry? Wells? The police?
不  现在没人能阻止我
No. Nobody can stop me now.
再也没有了
Not anymore.
那你打算怎么做
So... what's your plan?
你就打算杀死所有人吗
You're just gonna kill everyone?
不是所有人
Not everyone.
那你为什么把我关在这里
Then why are you keeping me here?
因为我不想再孤身一人
'Cause I don't want to be alone anymore.
我是绝不会和你在一起的
I am never going to be with you.
你以为你和我不一样
You think that you're not like me,
但我见过你内心的黑暗面  凯特琳
but I've seen the darkness inside of you, Caitlin.
正如冰霜杀手的内心一样
Just like it was inside Killer Frost.
你只需要  释放它
All you have to do... is unlock it.
酒馆
来了
There she is.
还是穿得跟个小孩子似的
Still refuse to dress like a grown-up, I see.
给他一瓶葡萄汽水
One grape soda.
不了  谢谢
Ah, no. I'm good. Thanks.
出什么事了
So...what's wrong?
什么  我非得出什么事
What? Something has to be wrong for me
才能找兄弟叙叙旧吗
to want to catch up with my brother?
你通常不就是无事不登三宝殿吗
Yeah, that's usually the way it works with you, isn't it?
其实  我只是觉得
Actually, I had this...
我应该来看看你
feeling that I should come see you
确保你没事
and make sure you're okay, so...
别告诉我  我又要被史纳特
Don't tell me I'm gonna be kidnapped
和他的纵火狂朋友绑架了
by Snart and his pyromaniac friend again.
是我们  你和我  他们绑架了我们俩
Us. You. Me. Us. They kidnapped both of us.
差点被冻坏双手的人
Yeah, well, you're not the one
又不是你
who almost had his hands frozen off.
幸好我还能弹钢琴
Lucky I can still play the piano.
虽然弹八度音阶时不如从前
Well, my octaves haven't quite been the same,
但这对你来说不重要
but not that that matters to you.
丹堤  我给你打了不止一次电话
Dante, I called you, more than once,
当然了  你没接
but, of course, you didn't answer.
我就说了  肯定是有事
Like I said. Only when something's wrong.
好吧
Yeah. Okay.
我不知我为什么会以为
I don't know why I thought
那件事就会改变一切
that whole experience-- that was it.
会拉近我们的距离
That was gonna bring us closer.
西斯科  我们长大后就没亲近过
Cisco, we haven't been close since we were kids.
我认为这点是不会改变的
I don't think anything's ever gonna change that.
好  我们晚点再带一些必需品过来
All right. We'll bring down some more supplies later.
用这个和我们保持联络
How you can reach us.
我们到底要在这里待多久
And exactly how long are we supposed to be in here?
直到有人放你们出去
Until someone lets you out.
虽说一点都不理想  但极速在这里
This isn't ideal-- none of it-- but Zoom's here,
在搞定他之前  我们只能这么做
and until he's taken care of, this is what we're doing.
现在这里对你们俩来说是最安全的
This is the safest place for the two of you right now.
你们打算怎么做
What are you gonna do?
-竭尽全力  -乔  让我帮帮忙吧
- Whatever we can. - Joe, let me do something.
沃利  现在你什么也帮不了
Wally, there isn't anything you can do right now.
待在这里
Sit tight.
好吧  那...
Okay, well, what about the...
厕所呢
bathroom?
这里至少有无线网络吧
This room have Wi-Fi at least?
沃利和杰西都安顿好了
Wally and Jesse are all good.
谢谢
Thank you.
这就是帮巴里恢复速度的公式
So this is what it takes to get Barry his speed back.
是的
Yeah, yeah.
并不简单  但就快完成了
It's not uncomplicated, but almost there.
我和你说过  一旦巴里下定决心
I told you before, once Barry makes up his mind,
就无人能动摇
it's impossible to change it.
那我们就得说服他  这是唯一的办法
Well, then we need to convince him that this is the only way,
以免他决定不做  对吧
before he decides not to do it, right?
我们不该说服任何人
Shouldn't have to convince anyone
去做任何违背意愿的事
to do anything against his will.
乔  我们说的是巴里  对吧
Joe, we're talking about Barry, right?
我无法想像
I mean, I can't-- I can't imagine
你不是这么看的
you don't feel the same way.
眼下我不知道怎么做才是对的了
I mean, right now, I don't know what the right thing to do is.
在我看来清楚得很
Seems clear to me.
这不只关乎你的儿子
This isn't just about your son.
亨利  这关乎中城的人们
Henry, this is about the people in Central City.
关乎拯救那些人  阻止极速
About saving those people. This is about stopping Zoom.
你女儿已经安全了
Your daughter is safe.
这么做可能会要我儿子的命
This could kill my son.
我不会让这种事发生的
I'm not gonna let that happen.
上次他被闪电击中
The last time he was struck by lightning,
昏迷了九个月
he was in a coma for nine months.
-这要怎么说  -我知道我在做什么
- How did that happen? - I know what I'm doing.
你在乱搞一些你无法掌控的事物
You are messing with something that is out of your control.
就算成功了又怎样  然后呢
And what if it did work? I mean, what then?
乔  他要去对抗极速
Joe? He goes up against Zoom,
那怪物之前弄伤了他  差点害死他
the monster that snapped his back and almost killed him,
还夺走了他现在坚信自己必须拥有
and then took the one thing that he's convinced now that he needs
才能完整的东西
in order to make him whole?
只有这样  这是唯一的办法
This is the way. This is the only way.
中城的人们需要闪电侠
The people of Central City need The Flash.
他来了
Guys.
我知道你们都关心我  各有各的方式
I know that you care about me, each of you, in your own way,
而你们在这事上看法不一样
and you all have your own point of view on this,
但这事决定权在我
but this decision is mine.
我必须自己做出决定
I have to make it on my own.
能调到钻石队比赛的台吗
Can you put the Diamonds game on?
体育节目  这是个暗示
Ah, sports. That's my cue.
好吧  今天很开心
All right, well, this was fun.
-玩得很开心  -等等
- Um...good hang. - Whoa. Wait.
把单买了再走
Gonna take care of that, right?
是你邀请我的  哥们
Dude, you invited me.
真是不可理喻
Unbelievable.
等等
Hey, hold up!
极速占领了中城警局
糟了
Oh, no.
怎么了  西斯科
What? Cisco?
等等我
Hey, wait.
把我送回家
Yo! I need a lift home.
你连台车也没有吗
You still don't have a car?
我可没有
Some of us don't have
一队公车能随意调遣
a fleet of company cars at our disposal.
我很快就有车了  哥们
Dude, it's on the way.
那好  走吧
Yeah, okay. Come on.
你没事吧
You okay?
你好  震波
Hello, Vibe.
冷静  收割者  我跟你没过节
Simmer down, Reaper. We got no beef with you.
或许吧
Maybe not,
但我跟你有过节  震波
but I've got beef with you, Vibe.
为什么他一直那么叫你
Why does he keep calling you that?
我也不知道
I don't know.
你杀了我弟弟  现在该你偿命了
You killed my brother, so, now, you die.
天啊
Oh, my God.
这不是《公主新娘》里的桥段吗
You're "Princess Bride"-ing me right now!
你肯定把我跟别人搞混了  埃尼戈
You must have me mixed up with somebody else, Inigo.
并没有  我弟弟是回波
I don't think so. My brother was Reverb.
想起来了吗
Remember now?
-快跑  -他长得...
- Move! - He looks...
-快上车  -他长得像...
- Get--get--get in the van! - He looks like...
快点
Now!
我就知道有问题
I knew there was something wrong.
我们每次见面都会被
Every time I see you, we get attacked
拿着狂暴武器的疯子攻击
by lunatics with crazy weapons!
快点  不然那东西会把我们炸死的
Come on! He's gonna blast us with that thing!
不会的
No, he's not!
快走  快走
Go! Go!
你得跟我说清楚这次到底
You want to tell me exactly what you've gotten us
怎么回事
into this time?
他自称破裂者
He calls himself Rupture.
我的地球上极速手下的另一超能力者
Another meta-human under Zoom's control from my Earth.
很好  他叫了更多的朋友过来
Great, so he's bringing more of his friends over.
我说过他会这么做
That's what I told you he would do.
极速肯定骗假丹堤
Okay, well, Zoom must've lied to fake-Dante
我就是杀死回波的凶手
and told him I was the one who killed Reverb,
因为那家伙想杀死我
'cause dude wants me dead.
我们得有所行动
We got to do something.
你对他还有什么了解吗
What else do you know about him?
他的力量来源于手中的镰刀
He gets his power from that scythe he wields.
有道理  那玩意差点拆掉了半辆车
Thing's legit too--it almost took half the van with him.
那好  那就这么办
All right, then that's what we need to do.
我们得想办法拿走他手中的镰刀
We need to figure out a way to get it away from him.
没错  好吧
Right. Okay, all right.
我肯定会想到办法的
I'm sure I can come up with something.
我还得想办法跟丹堤解释
I just have to figure out a way to not tell Dante
为什么这疯子跟他长得一样
why this psychopath looks exactly like him.
你知道该怎么办
You know what you need to do.
让我自己待会
I need a minute.
也不是什么很难的选择  对不对
It should be an easy decision. Why isn't it?
这又不像
I mean, it's not like you're picking out
选哪件毛衣穿那么简单
what sweater you're gonna wear.
再经历一次粒子加速器爆炸
Getting hit by another particle accelerator explosion?
要是出了差错怎么办
I mean, come on. What if something goes wrong?
要是...
What if...
我还以为把我爸爸叫来能容易些
I thought bringing my dad here would make this easier.
没想到却更加艰难了
It's just made it a lot harder.
是啊  我能理解他不希望你这么做
Yeah, I can understand him not wanting you to do it.
他只希望你能平安
He just wants you to be safe.
那你呢
What about you?
如果你受到伤害  我不知道自己
I mean, I don't know if I could go through
还能不能像上次那样挺过来
what I went through last time if you get hurt.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
不太好
Not really.
怎么了
What's up?
你还记得我曾跟你说过
Do you remember when I told you
如果心中没有什么牵挂
that I didn't want you going to Earth-2
就不要再去地球二了吗
if you felt like you didn't have anything left here?
记得...因为帕蒂走了
Yeah...because Patty left.
不单单是因为帕蒂
It wasn't just because of Patty.
什么意思
What do you mean?
巴里  一直都有个人等你回家
Barry, you've always had someone to come home to.
我
Me.
我最近考虑了很多...
I've just been thinking a lot lately...
我们的事
about us.
威尔斯说我们未来是夫妻
What Wells said about us being married in the future.
在地球二上
And on Earth-2.
我不禁这样想...
And I can't help wondering if...
也许我们注定会在一起
maybe we were meant to be together.
那...
So...
我去年向你表白的时候...
when I told you how I felt about you last year...
当时我还没意识到
I wasn't available in that way.
但...但现在我意识到了
But...but I am now.
为什么这会跟我说这些话
Why are you telling me this now?
因为  巴里  我想让你知道
Because, Barry, I need you to know
我不介意
that it doesn't matter to me
你是不是闪电侠
if you're The Flash or not.
巴里  我只想知道和你有没有未来
You, Barry--that's who I want to see if I have a future with.
我是说
I mean...
当然前提是你还有那想法
if you still want that too, of course.
我得去看看杰西和沃利要不要帮忙
I should go see if Jesse and Wally need anything.
中城警局
快
Come on.
太棒了
Yes!
情况如何
And?
他跑了  但我会找到他的
He got away, but I'll find him.
以后再说
Later.
他要为他对我弟弟所做的事付出代价
He needs to pay for what he did to my brother!
他会的  以后再说  破裂者
And he will. Later, Rupture!
你想让我做什么
What do you want me to do?
警察又聚集起来了
The police have gathered again.
他们以为我就饶过他们了
They think I've spared their lives.
今晚  让他们知道自己想错了
Tonight... show them they're wrong.
你不满意吗
You disapprove?
你说了你会饶了他们
You said you would spare them.
我要给他们个教训
I need to teach them a lesson.
所以你才要改变声音吗
Is that why you change your voice?
这样大家都会怕你吗
So that everyone will be afraid of you?
我不是魔鬼
I'm not a monster!
你之前说过
As you once said...
我只是个魔鬼
I'm nothing but a monster.
破裂者今晚
将袭击吉特斯
我们现在能出去了吗
Can we come out now?
不能
No!
这里有什么东西在闪
Something's blinking over here.
破裂者今晚
将袭击吉特斯
-从中城警局发来的  -是凯特琳
- From CCPD. - That's Caitlin.
凯特琳怎么了
What about Caitlin?
她给我们发了个消息
She sent us a message.
破裂者今晚要袭击吉特斯
Rupture is gonna attack Jitters tonight.
我们得行动了  巴里
We got to move, Barry.
你要怎么做  小拳王
What are you gonna do, slugger?
闪电侠重生可能是阻止极速以及
Having The Flash might be the best way to stop Zoom
他带来的超能力者最好的办法
and all the metas he's sending over.
但前提是我们确定
But, look, until we know for sure
引爆加速器有用  不然风险太大了
that setting off the accelerator will work, it's too risky.
对我和整个城市都太危险了
Not just for me. For the entire city.
如果没有控制好爆炸
Countless others that would be affected
无数人将会受到影响
if the explosion is not contained.
-是  但艾伦  -别说了  威尔斯
- Yes, but Allen-- - Stop, Wells.
我很抱歉  我已经决定了
Look, I'm sorry. I've made up my mind.
对不起
Sorry.
我们得想办法
We're gonna have to figure out
不靠闪电侠也能阻止他们
how to do this without The Flash.
吉特斯咖啡店
乔  你联系上闪电侠了吗
Joe, did you reach The Flash?
他会来的
He'll be here.
很好  这些人马上就准备好了
Great, these guys are almost ready.
接"1"
Put it on "1"
我们都准备好了
Hey, we're all set up.
你确定这是最佳方案吗
Are you sure this is the best plan?
我知道你不能作为闪电侠来帮忙
Look, I know you can't help as The Flash,
但阻止极速的一个盟友可以告诉他
but stopping one of Zoom's cronies sends him a message
我们不会被吓倒
that we won't be intimidated.
你觉得我做了正确的决定吗
You think I made the right decision?
我不知道  巴仔
I don't know, Bare.
无论这个决定正确与否
Whether you made the right one or not,
你都得承担后果
you're gonna have to live with it.
是啊  好吧
Yeah. All right.
这是什么
What is this?
你去过另一个地球吗
You went to another Earth?
你不该看那个的
You weren't supposed to read that.
在你桌上放着  要寄给妈妈和我的
It was on your desk. It was addressed to Mom and me.
所以我就看了
So, yeah, I read it.
我现在得走了  我们之后再谈
Look, I got to go, okay? We'll talk about this later.
不  我们现在就要谈谈这个
No, man, we're gonna talk about this right now!
好  我们现在谈
Okay, let's talk about this now.
你想让我说什么
What did you want me to say?
"还好吗家人  我知道你估计不在乎
"What up, fam? I know you probably don't care,
但我要去另一个地球一段时间
But I'm going off to another Earth for a hot sec.
我要是没赶上回来吃晚饭
If I don't make it back in time for dinner,
可能是遇上麻烦了"
it probably didn't go so well."
你当初到底为什么要去
Why did you even go in the first place?
因为我的朋友需要我帮忙
Because my friends needed my help.
帮什么忙
What kind of help?
-他们需要我用震波  -震波
- They needed me to vibe. - Vibe?
那个袭击我们的疯子就这么叫你的
That's what that lunatic called you, who attacked us.
你到底瞒了我什么  西斯科
What aren't you telling me, Cisco?
我有超能力
I have powers.
超能力
Powers?
怎么  你是超能力者吗
What, you're, like, a meta-human?
两年前
I was affected
粒子加速器爆炸时我受到了影响
when the accelerator went off two years ago,
我现在能用震波看到别人
and now I see things, vibes...of people.
就像是幻视吗
Like visions?
所以你才给我打电话
So that's why you called me.
对
Yeah.
我看到了你  至少我以为那是你
I had one of you, or at least I thought it was you,
结果你那像魔兽世界里的二重身出现了
until your "World of Warcraf" doppelganger showed up.
你杀了他弟弟吗
You killed his brother?
我没有杀他弟弟  当然没有
No, I didn't kill his brother. Of course not.
这些事情你怎么都不告诉我呢
Why wouldn't you tell me any of this?
因为你是对的  就像你说的
Because you're right. It's just like you said.
多年来我们关系都很疏远
We haven't been close in years and...
无论什么都无法改变这一事实
and there's nothing we can do to change that.
我得走了
Look, I got to go.
待在这里等我  好吗
Just wait for me here, okay?
吉特斯咖啡店
准备好了吗  西斯科
You all set, Cisco?
准备好了
Yeah, we're set.
他来了
Here he comes.
大家都去哪了
Now, where has everybody gone?
闪电侠  我可没想到你会来
Flash? Not who I was expecting,
但用你来热热身也不错
but you'll be a nice warm-up.
太慢了  破裂者
Too slow, Rupture.
来吧  闪电侠
Come on, Flash!
好了  该拿奥斯卡奖了
All right. Time to win an Oscar.
开始吧
Let's do it.
起来
Get up.
我们就是你要找的人吗
Are we the guys you were looking for?
希望你喜欢独处
Hope you like being alone,
因为你在铁山监狱里谁也见不到
'cause you won't be talking to anyone at Iron Heights.
西斯科  我们抓到他了  一切顺利
Cisco, we got him. All good.
退后  别拍了
Get back! Get that camera back.
中城吉特斯咖啡厅发生恐怖事件
来自吉特斯咖啡厅的突发新闻
Breaking news coming out of Jitters coffee shop.
中城时报得知  一名超能力者
CCPN has learned that a meta-human
在与闪电侠发生争执后被捕了
was just apprehended after an altercation with The Flash.
你告诉了他们破裂者要来
You told them Rupture was coming.
怎么告诉的
How?
你真机智  对不对
Oh, you... are smart, aren't you?
你背叛了我
You betrayed me!
你说过会饶了他们
You said you would spare them.
我想...
I guess...
现在我们扯平了
now we're even.
杰伊  不要
Jay, no!
我的名字是极速
My name...is Zoom.
天呐  不要
Oh, my God. No!
中城吉特斯咖啡厅发生恐怖事件
你们一定要拍下这个
Make sure you get this.
-怎么会  -他们必须撤离
- What the...? - They got to get out of there.
大家快走
Everybody move!
巴里  别
Barry, don't!
不
No!
我告诉过你违背我是什么后果
I told you what would happen if you disobeyed me.
住手  住手  天呐
Hey, stop! Stop! God...
你的态度我们已经很清楚了
you've made your point.
还不够清楚
Not quite yet.
你比你哥哥更让我失望
You're an even bigger disappointment than your brother.
中城吉特斯咖啡厅发生恐怖事件
中城的市民
Central City...
你们在街上看到的闪电侠是假的
the Flash you've seen in your streets is a fake.
寄予你们希望的全息投影
A hologram meant to give you hope.
但希望已经不在
But there is no more hope,
闪电侠已经不在
there is no more Flash,
已经没人能阻止你们的城市...
and there's no one left to protect your city...
被我摧毁
from me.
告诉你手里剩下的警力  队长
Tell the rest of your force, Captain,
他们维护治安的日子结束了
that their policing days are over.
你们还活着  要感谢凯特琳
You're only alive because of Caitlin.
再敢搞这种名堂
Try something like this again,
那么我对她的感情
and my affection for her
也将无法阻止我杀掉你们
won't stop me from killing you...
或杀掉城里所有的人
or the rest of this city!
你看到了吗
Did you see this?
这就你去做的事情  对吗
That's what you left to go do, wasn't it?
听着兄弟  我知道你生我的气
Look, man. I know you're mad at me.
我们之间疏远了很久
We haven't been close in a long time.
我想做出改变
I want things to change.
你是我哥哥
You're my brother.
好的
Okay.
你知道那面墙不会随便为你打开
You know that wall's not just gonna open for you, right?
也许会
It might.
相信我  不会的
Yeah, trust me. It won't.
我们不该在这里
We shouldn't be in here.
我们应该出去和他们一起
We should be out there with them.
为什么  让极速再次抓走我们吗
Why? So Zoom can take us again?
-不  我们可以帮忙阻止他  -怎么阻止
No, so we can help stop him. - What are we gonna do?
我们又没什么超能力
I mean, we don't have any powers.
我不知道
I don't know.
不过你解那些难题还挺快的
Hey, you're pretty quick at solving unsolvable problems.
我们想想办法
Let's figure it out.
看看我能做点什么
I will see what I can do.
用不了多久了
It won't be long now.
他比在地球二时速度更快了
He's moving faster than he ever did on my Earth.
接下来呢
So what's next?
接下来他会尽可能召集超能力者
Next, he'll recruit every meta-human he can find,
迫使他们听从他的指示
and then force them to do what he wants.
还有多少超能力者
How many could be left?
我们不是消灭掉大多数了吗
We defeated most of them, didn't we?
没有  你们还差得远
No. You're not even close.
这个
This...
是地球二的超能力者名单
is a list of meta-humans from my Earth.
还只是已知的
Ones that are known, anyway.
粒子加速器爆炸
The particle accelerator explosion
在地球二得到了控制
was contained on my Earth.
这里却没有
That didn't happen here.
那这里为何看不到其他超能力者
Then why wouldn't we know about other meta-humans here?
因为有闪电侠在
Because of the Flash.
现在所有人知道闪电侠不在了
And now that everyone knows that he's not around...
他们会从阴暗的角落里一个个爬出来
They'll start coming out of the woodwork.
我们无法确定
We don't know that.
你还需要什么证据
What more do you need?
我说过他会召集超能力者
I told you he'd recruit meta-humans.
我们已经看到了
We've seen him do that.
我说过他会杀掉那些警察
I told you he would kill those officers.
我们也看到了
We saw him do that too.
你还需要什么
What more do you need?
咱们开始吧  我想通了
Let's do it. I want to do it.
今晚有个被极速杀害的警察  他有儿子
One of the cops that Zoom killed tonight, he had a son.
和我妈妈被杀时我的年龄一样
Same age I was when Mom was murdered.
现在  一个孩子将在没有家长的环境中长大
And now, another kid has to grow up without one of their parents
就因为闪电侠没有去阻止那个怪物
because The Flash wasn't there to stop that monster.
我把能力给了极速  让这座城市失去保护
I left this city unprotected by giving up my powers to Zoom.
我给了他统治这个地球的机会
I enabled him to rule this Earth.
我得恢复我的超能力
I need my powers back.
咱们开始吧
Let's do it.
让我们炸掉粒子加速器
Let's set off the particle accelerator.
所以这原理是什么
So how does this work?
这是邪恶版
It's an abbreviated version
威尔斯建的加速器缩略版
of the accelerator evil Wells built,
不过哈里会隔离反物质和暗能量
except Harry is isolating the antimatter and dark energy
把它导向巴里  而不是整个城市
to direct it to Barry instead of the entire city.
很好  我们最不需要的
Good. Last thing we need
就是中城里出现更多的超能力者了
is more meta-humans running around Central City.
所以  只要巴里进去
So...Barry just gets in,
我们把它打开  这样就可以了吗
we turn it on, and that's it?
是的
Yeah.
不  也不尽然
No. Not exactly.
除了要还原曾经发生过的
In addition to recreating what happened with
粒子加速器爆炸之外
the particle accelerator explosion,
我们还要还原发生在巴里身上的事
we also have to recreate what happened to Barry.
被闪电击中
Getting struck by lightning.
没错
That's right.
等下  所以你要怎么做到这一点
Wait, so how are you gonna do that?
外面甚至都没下雨
It's not even raining outside.
拉蒙  你有天气魔棒
Well, Ramon, you have the wand.
是我给马克·马登做的那个吗
The one I made for Mark Mardon?
不  是你为哈利·波特展会做的那个
No, the one you built for the Harry Potter convention.
没错  当然是你给马登做的那个
Yes, of course, the one you built for Mardon.
你怎么知道哈利·波特展会的
How do you know about the Harry Potter convention?
-拿着天气魔棒  去屋顶  -为什么是屋顶
- Get the wand. Get on the roof. - Why the roof?
因为我们需要一个引雷针
Because we're gonna need a lightning rod,
而这个  拉蒙  就靠你了
and that, Ramon, is gonna be you.
好了  我到屋顶了
All right, I'm on the roof.
我之前都没上来过
I've never actually been up here before.
我觉得我能从这里看到我的公寓
I think I can see my apartment from here.
现在直接走到卫星那  拉蒙
Now head straight to the satellite, Ramon.
等我给你信号的时候
When I give you the signal,
你就在你上方制造一个闪电风暴
you're gonna create a lightning storm above you.
所以我就得这么站在一个
So I'm just supposed to stand here in the middle
-闪电风暴的中央是吗  -讲真的  拉蒙
- of a lightning storm? - Really, Ramon.
被闪电击中的可能性真的很小
Chances of being struck are slim, indeed.
是啊  只要你不是制造闪电的那个人
Yeah, not when you're the one causing it.
我们只要有一道闪电击中卫星就行
All we need is one lightning bolt to strike the satellite.
卫星的电路连接着有缺口的那个房间
The satellite circuitry's connected to the breach room.
巴里就在缺口房间里  赶紧开始吧
Barry's in the breach room. Just do it.
知道了  我开始了
Yeah. I'm doing it.
莫扎特可要小心了
Mozart better watch out.
西斯科·拉蒙要制造一些不好的东西了
Cisco Ramon's about to conduct something nasty.
这些夹钳不好受  但它们是必需的
You're gonna feel these clamps, but they're necessary.
-你还好吗  -恩  你呢
- You good? - Yeah. You?
我会没事的 乔
I'll be fine, Joe.
巴里  无论发生什么
Barry, whatever happens,
我对你的感情都不会改变
it will never change the way that I feel about you.
儿子
Son...
如果你不想的话  你不必这么做
you don't have to do this if you don't want to.
作为闪电侠  才是我更好的一面
Being The Flash... that's the best version of me.
如果我没有速度  我就再也不是那个人了
If I don't have my speed, I'll never be that person anymore.
我必须得这么做
I have to do this.
好吧
OK
你准备好了吗  艾伦
You ready, Allen?
那好
All right, then.
我们开始吧
Here we go.
你就想成是用短路点火发动汽车  好吗
Think of it as hotwiring a car, right?
就如同墙里有一个发动机
So there's a motor inside the wall.
我们要做的就是提供电力
So all we have to do is provide electricity
-来开启它  -没错
- to make it turn on. - Exactly.
所以我们只要在这里做一点
So we just do a little here...
瞧  这就好啦
And voila!
你感觉到了吗
Do you feel that?
是的  发生了什么
Yeah, what's happening?
粒子变得不稳定了
Particles are becoming unstable.
拉蒙  准备好
Ramon, get ready!
我马上会把化学物质释放到他体内
I'm gonna release the chemicals into his system.
为什么你要做这个
Why are you doing this?
巴里被闪电击中的那晚
The night Barry was struck by lightning,
他在做指纹分析
he was doing fingerprint analysis.
那些化学物质当时进入了他的体内
Those chemicals got in his system then,
现在它们也得进去
and they are going in now.
所以你要把它们注入他体内
So you're injecting them into him?
我们要还原当晚
We have to recreate everything
发生在巴里身上的一切
that happened to Barry that night.
我没事  爱瑞斯
I'm okay, Iris!
-坚持住  巴里  -我的天
- Hold on, Barry. - God!
-他要进入流体静力状态了  -马上就好  马上
- He's going hydrostatic. - Almost there. Almost there.
-威尔斯  -快好了
- Wells! - Almost there.
准备好了吗  拉蒙
Ready, Ramon?
准备好了
Ready!
// 注射状态: 确认
-现在  -呼神护卫
- Now! - Expecto Patronum!
我的天呐  起效了
Great Scott! It's working!
不
No!
开始对撞
Initiating collision.
巴里
Barry!
成功了
It worked!
大家都还好吗
Is everyone okay?
发生了什么
What happened?
不
No!
不  你对我的儿子做了什么
No. What did you do to my son?
你以为
You thought
你能把闪电侠的速度还给他吗
you could give The Flash his speed back?
干的漂亮
Well done.
你反而把给他杀了
You killed him instead.